ParkIQ — AI-powered parking enforcement intelligence,
built on 115,000 real Bengaluru traffic police records.
Bengaluru loses 60 minutes daily per commuter.
Officers are deployed reactively with no visibility into where violations peak.
Two real datasets: 298,450 BTP violation records
and 8,173 ASTRAM traffic incidents — both covering the same 54 police stations.
The live heatmap plots 20,000 GPS-verified violation points
across Bengaluru, weighted by vehicle severity from scooter to truck.
Top hotspot: Safina Plaza Junction with 5,882 violations.
The top 5 junctions account for 25% of all named-junction violations.
Peak enforcement window: 10 AM IST.
Mondays through Fridays see highest counts. Night drives spike between 2–5 AM.
Cross-correlating with ASTRAM incidents:
stations with active enforcement show fewer traffic events.
10 officers assigned to priority zones across 3 shifts.
4,706 violations addressable per deployment cycle.
Cars are the top offender type.
The vehicle-by-hour heatmap reveals when each type causes the most blockages.
Priority score = 40% frequency
+ 30% peak-hour + 20% incident correlation + 10% severity.
From raw CSV data to deployable patrol schedules —
a complete intelligence pipeline, real-time ready for BTP.
ParkIQ: making Bengaluru's roads smarter, one junction at a time.
Gridlock Hackathon 2.0 · Problem Statement 1.